A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Countries, Series E FA341
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Countries, Series E
1931-1972
1945-1971
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich) (1908-1979)
FA341
27.03 Cubic Feet 70 letter boxes, 1 half-letter box, 1 half-legal box
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Material in the Rockefeller family collections that provides the names, correspondence, or activities of living members of the Rockefeller family, and/or documents the net wealth of any Rockefeller family members, is restricted. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement note
The Countries Series is arranged alphabetically by country name. Subject files are arranged alphabetically thereunder.
Scope and Contents note
This series contains Nelson A. Rockefeller's correspondence with private individuals and representatives of institutions and governments in 87 foreign countries. With some exceptions, this material consists mainly of financial appeals from individuals and institutions. Appeals from individuals include requests for money for such things as starting a business, traveling to the United States, or publishing a book. The range of institutions includes churches, universities, health centers, and businesses. Because Mr. Rockefeller followed his family's philanthropic tradition of aiding people through institutions rather than individually, nearly all of the personal appeals were declined. Only those institutional appeals that fell within Mr. Rockefeller's areas of interest were favorably answered. Most of the declination letters were written by members of Mr. Rockefeller's staff on his behalf.
While some scattered documents are dated as early as 1931, the bulk of the material covers the period from 1945 to 1971. In accordance with Rockefeller family office filing procedures, appeals from individuals dated prior to 1958 were discarded by the family office staff prior to inclusion in the archive.
The material consists of all manner of correspondence and sometimes includes newspaper clippings or photographs. There are also background reports on individuals and institutions in which Mr. Rockefeller took an interest. Much of the correspondence, including the appeals, is from his foreign friends and acquaintances. Some of them sent Mr. Rockefeller reports on political and economic conditions in various countries, particularly emerging nations and developing countries. Correspondence with friends and acquaintances also includes invitations, regrets, announcements, and acknowledgements.
More than half of the material in this series is from individuals in Latin America, reflecting Mr. Rockefeller's deep interest in that region. These individuals include business leaders, political leaders, diplomats, and artists. The Latin American-related material complements other series in the Nelson A. Rockefeller Papers, namely Series B: AIA-IBEC Files and Series O: Washington, DC Files. Together, these materials offer a nearly complete record of Rockefeller's interest in the economic, political, and cultural affairs of Latin America.
Public health -- Latin America; Social problems -- Latin America; International economic relations; International relations; Arts; Art, Primitive; Agriculture -- Latin America; Agriculture; Education -- Latin America; Philanthropy; Government policy; Economic policy; Developing countries; Business enterprises, Foreign; Civic improvement; Education
- Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous (A-F), 1954-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Appeal letters from countries that don't have separate folders (e.g., Baltic States, Burma, Cameroon)
  - Miscellaneous (G-M), 1954-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Appeal letters from countries that don't have separate folders (e.g., Jordan, Madagascar, Mauritania)
  - Miscellaneous (P-Z), 1954-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Appeal letters from countries that don't have separate folders (e.g., Senegal)
- Africa
  Africa
  - Africa - General Correspondence (A-C), 1958-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Appeals, previous to 1958 destroyed.
  - Africa - General Correspondence (G-J), 1958-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Africa - General Correspondence (K-M), 1958-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Africa - General Correspondence (N-Z), 1949, 1958-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Africa - Map of Regional Groupings - "New York Times", January 26, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Shows regional groupings.
  - Africa - Congo, 1945-1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Africa - Congo - Colleges and Schools, 1959-1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Africa - East Central Rwanda, Republic of, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Africa - Ethiopia, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Africa - French Equatorial Africa - Lambarene, Dr. Schweitzer, 1952-1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Africa - Ghana, 1958-1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Africa - Kilimanjaro African Coffee, Inc. - Kilimanjaro Native Co-operative Union - Arthur T. Gist, Jr. President, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Africa - Liberia, 1947-1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Africa - Nigeria - General (A-M), 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Africa - Nigeria - General (N-Z), 1952-1971 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Africa - Nigeria - Najeube, J. E. O., 1956, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Previous to 1958 destroyed.
  - Africa - Nigeria - Churches, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Africa - Nigeria - Government, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Correspondence re NAR meeting with T. F. Griffin of the Ministry of Trade and Industry.
  - Africa - Rhodesia, 1958-1969 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Africa - South Africa - General, 1959-1970 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Appeals.
  - Africa - South Africa - Colleges and Schools, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Appeals for St. Charles College and Pius XII College.
  - Africa - South Africa - Industrialization, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Addresses by Dr. H. J. Van Eck on industrialization in South Africa, summary of lectures.
  - Africa - Uganda, East Africa, 1964-1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Africa - Uganda, East Africa - Kampala - Makerere College, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Africa - Printed Material - Africa, Basic Economic Data, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Belgian Congo, Egypt, Gold Coast, Kenya, Liberia, Nigeria, Rhodesia, South Africa, Uganda, Sudan.
  - Africa - Printed Material - Nigerian Railway, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    Consulting engineers' report, February, 1956; traffic survey in Zaria Bauchi, and Bornu Provinces, 1955; Annual Report on Government Railway, 1954-1955.
  - Africa - General and Miscellaneous, 1948-1955 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Pamphlets on African art, reports of Nigerian Antiquities Service; maps; pamphlets for travel in Africa; "The Forum" (Johannesburg), July, 1956; Material on industries in Rhodesia and South Africa; Firestone Operations in Liberia.
  - Africa - General and Miscellaneous - "Liberia Today", 1953-1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    United States Business Performance Abroad; various issues of "Liberia Today"; miscellaneous material on Liberia.
  - Africa - General and Miscellaneous - "Belgian Congo Today", 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    3 issues of "Belgian Congo Today"; miscellaneous material on Congo.
- Argentina
  Argentina
  - Argentina - General (A-C), 1947-1971 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Argentina - General (D-H), 1945-1971 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Argentina - General (I-N), 1946-1971 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Argentina - General (N-R), 1952-1971 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Argentina - General (S-Z), 1943-1971 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Argentina - Cantilo, Jose Maria, 1946-1949 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    Appeal to NAR to assist Compania Argentina de Representaciones Exportacion e Importacion (CAREI).
  - Argentina - Carcano, Miguel Angel, 1945-1962 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    Correspondence between NAR and Dr. Carcano, Argentine diplomat. Asks NAR for aid in finding a publisher for an account of his diplomatic career, sent NAR a copy of his tract on Argentine admission to the United Nations. Some informal correspondence from the 1940s.
  - Argentina - Clippings and Printed Matter, 1946-1956 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Argentina - Colleges and Schools, 1956-1966 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Argentina - Government, 1947-1969 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    Correspondence re: to the political situation and reports to and by NAR.
  - Argentina - Migone, Raul, 1945-1969 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    Correspondence and proposals relating to a variety of matters, mostly unofficial. Migone was Argentine ambassador to United States.
  - Argentina - Ocampo, Victoria, Sur Magazine, 1946-1962 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    Correspondence with Mrs. Ocampo, an Argentinean writer, and NAR.
  - Argentina - Oliver, Maria Rosa, 1943-1948 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    Latin American advisor to Office of Inter-American Affairs, Argentine writer. File contains wartime reports to NAR re: Latin American and Post war correspondence between Miss Oliver, in Argentina, and NAR. Correspondence deals with politics in Argentina, including rise of Peron.
  - Argentina - Trade Agreements, 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    Clippings, correspondence and memoranda re: United States-Latin America trade agreement.
  - Argentina - Williams, Thomas J., 1944-1968 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    Correspondence between NAR and Williams re: business and public affairs in which Williams felt NAR would be interested. Williams was a businessman who spent some 30 years in Latin America. Some correspondence re" the Williams Foundation set-up in honor of Williams, between NAR and the Foundation director.
- Australia
  Australia
  - Australia - General (A-M), 1948-1971 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Australia - General (N-Z), 1948-1971 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Australia - Right Honorable Lord Casey, Governor General and Lady Casey (Marie), 1967 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    Memos re: NAR's gift and call upon the Australian Governor General and his wife during their visit to the United States.
  - Australia - Australian Government, 1956-1967 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    Correspondence, copies of statements re: NAR acquaintance with various Australian leaders. Correspondence and press release concerning NAR talk at memorial service for Prime Minister Holt (1967); 1967 visit of the Governor General to United States.
  - Australia - Museum of Modern Art of Australia, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    Correspondence between NAR and various Australians involved with the Museum. Requests for NAR's guidance and "moral support."
- Austria
  Austria
  - Austria, 1953-1970 (Box 8, Folder 53)
- Bahamas
  Bahamas
  - Bahamas - Nassau (New Province Island), 1958-1967 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Bahamas - Nassau, Eleuthera, Abaco, Andros - General, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    Appeals, memos from John Camp on his visit to the Bahamas, his meeting with the new premier, Pindling, NAR correspondence with Premier Pindling.
- Belgium
  Belgium
  - Belgium - General (A-G), 1958-1971 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    Appeals; memo on stag party for Prince Albert in New York; correspondence re: NAR visit to Belgium, 1963; the Queen's visit to the United States; a memo on past Rockefeller contact with Belgium.
  - Belgium - General (H-Z), 1958-1971 (Box 8, Folder 57)
- Bolivia
  Bolivia
  - Bolivia - General (A-Z), 1946-1970 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    Appeals, NAR letter of 1969 regretting inability to meet with Bolivian ambassador and three other Latin American ambassadors.
  - Bolivia - Andrade, Victor, March 1945 - October 1957 (Box 9, Folder 59)
    Correspondence between Mr. Andrade and NAR on wide range of matters - Bolivian-United States relations, Bolivian politics, Brazil, Ecuador, and U.S. Latin American ties in general. 1970 crrespondence re: Andrade's exile. Correspondence re: Andrade's son's attendance at West Point.
  - Bolivia - Andrade, Victor, June 1959 - November 1965 (Box 9, Folder 60)
    Correspondence between Mr. Andrade and NAR on wide range of matters - Bolivian-United States relations, Bolivian politics, Brazil, Ecuador, and U.S. Latin American ties in general. 1970 correspondence re: Andrade's exile. Correspondence re: Andrade's son's attendance at West Point.
  - Bolivia - Andrade, Victor - Mario & Lupita - Institute of International Education Correspondence, Account Closed May 1965 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Bolivia - Andrade, Victor, January 1966 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Bolivia - Government, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 63)
    Clippings and copies of NAR telegrams on death of President Barrientos.
  - Bolivia - Lozada, Enrique, 1941-1969 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    Bolivian diplomat, worked in Office of Inter-American Affairs. Correspondence on a variety of official and unofficial matters. Congratulations on son's job. NAR jelps Lozada find a job.
  - Bolivia - Martinez, Vargas, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    Ambassador to United States from Bolivia. Correspondence in which NAR recommends Mr. Robert Camp for a position.
  - Bolivia - Schools and Colleges, 1952, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Bolivia - Toro, R. David - General, 1948, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 67)
    Former President of Bolivia. NAR writes letter of reference.
- Brazil
  Brazil
  - Brazil - General Correspondence, 1945-1971 (Box 10, Folder 68)
    Correspondence re: health programs in Brazil, copies of reports on economic development.
  - Brazil - Clippings - Printed Material - General, 1946-1956 (Box 10, Folder 69)
    Clippings and translations of clippings on economic and political developments in Brazil. Sketchy.
  - Brazil - General (A), 1945-1971 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Brazil - General - Amazon River Basin Foundation, 1945-1971 (Box 10, Folder 71)
    Appeals to NAR and Rockefeller Brothers Fund on projects for economic development of the Amazon River Basin Foundation. Declined.
  - Brazil - General (Ba), 1945-1971 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Brazil - General (Be-Br), 1945-1971 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Brazil - General (Ca), 1945-1971 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Brazil - General (Ce-Cu), 1945-1971 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Brazil - General (D), 1945-1971 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - Brazil - General (E-F), 1945-1971 (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - Brazil - General (G), 1945-1971 (Box 12, Folder 78)
  - Brazil - General (H-I), 1945-1971 (Box 12, Folder 79)
  - Brazil - General (J-K), 1945-1971 (Box 12, Folder 80)
  - Brazil - General (L), 1945-1971 (Box 12, Folder 81)
  - Brazil - General (M), 1945-1971 (Box 12, Folder 82)
  - Brazil - General (N), 1945-1971 (Box 13, Folder 83)
  - Brazil - General (O), 1945-1971 (Box 13, Folder 84)
  - Brazil - General (Pa), 1945-1971 (Box 13, Folder 85)
  - Brazil - General (Pi), 1945-1971 (Box 13, Folder 86)
  - Brazil - General (Q-R), 1945-1971 (Box 13, Folder 87)
  - Brazil - General (Sa-Se), 1945-1971 (Box 13, Folder 88)
  - Brazil - General (Si), 1945-1971 (Box 13, Folder 89)
  - Brazil - General (So), 1945-1971 (Box 13, Folder 90)
  - Brazil - General (T-Z), 1945-1971 (Box 14, Folder 91)
  - Brazil - Alvez De Lima, Roberto, 1948-1971 (Box 14, Folder 92)
    Old friend of NAR. Congratulations, exchanges of greetings, unsuccessful attempts to see NAR when in New York and appeals by Alvez's wife for support for a center for crippled children.
  - Brazil - Andrade, Joao Napoleao de, 1960-1969 (Box 14, Folder 93)
    President of ABCAR (Associacao Brasileira de Credito e Assistencia Rural - Brazilian Association of Credit and Rural Assistance) and ACAR (Associacao de Credito e Assistencia Rural - Association of Credit and Rural Assistance), 1960. Received Lane Bryant International Volunteer Award, 1960. Wedding invitation sent to NAR, 1969.
  - Brazil - American Chamber of Commerce for Brazil, Rio de Janeiro, 1952-1958 (Box 14, Folder 94)
    An invitation to NAR to speak to the Chamber, 1958; memoranda and correspondence re: Brazilian commerce.
  - Brazil - Aranha, Oswaldo (Brazilian Ambassador), 1946-1957 (Box 14, Folder 95)
    Brazilian ambassador and consul, foreign minister, friend of NAR. File contains personal greetings, clippings. NAR worked with Aranha at Council on Foreign Relations. Died 1960.
  - Brazil - Barbosa, Theodoro Quartim, 1947-1970 (Box 14, Folder 96)
    Association with NAR and International Basic Economy Corporation. Correspondence re: various business proposals. Personal correspondence and telegrams. Died 1968.
  - Brazil - Bittencourt, Paulo, Mrs., 1951-1969 (Box 14, Folder 97)
    Journalist. Arrested in 1969. Appeals to Hartford journalist for aid. NAR knew her and her husband who died in 1963. He was a journalist and was active in the Museum of Modern Art in Rio. File contains personal correspondence.
  - Brazil - Bouchas, Valentim F., 1947-1964 (Box 14, Folder 98)
    Friend of NAR. Appeals on behalf of friends for NAR help. Personal correspondence in file.
  - Brazil - Brazil Herald, Rio de Janeiro - English Language Daily, 1948-1952 (Box 14, Folder 99)
    Clippings. Correspondence re: obtaining advertising for the paper. Correspondents include John Montgomery, publisher.
  - Brazil - Chateaubriand, Assis, 1950-1968 (Box 14, Folder 100)
    Publisher, writer, owned radio and TV stations, in Brazilian politics. File includes correspondence re: Chateubriand's activities, manuscripts of his writings, clippings. Died 1968.
  - Brazil - Churches - General Correspondence, 1944-1971 (Box 15, Folder 101)
    Appeals. Appeal to NAR for support of Jacarezinho Cathedral. Referred by NAR to EMA in Sao Paulo.
  - Brazil - Colleges, 1944-1971 (Box 15, Folder 102)
  - Brazil - Costa Lima, Renato, 1953-1966 (Box 15, Folder 103)
    International Basic Economy Corporation consultant and President of the Brazilian Rural Society. Exchanges of letters of congratulations, NAR expresses gratuitude for Costa's IBEC work.
  - Brazil - Costa-e-Silva, Arthur da, President, 1966-1969 (Box 15, Folder 104)
    Memos to NAR from Berent Friele and others re: Silva's election, visit to United States, illness, and death. Died December, 1969.
  - Brazil - Cross, Cecil M. P., 1949, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 105)
    Former United States Consul General in Brazil. File shows efforts by NAR and others to prevent his transfer by State Department to Montreal, 1949. Praise of Cross's work. Letter to NAR re: private business.
  - Brazil - Daudt d'Oliveira, Joao, 1945-1952 (Box 15, Folder 106)
    Chairman, Inter-American Council of Commerce and Production. Copies of speeches sent to NAR, correspondence re: Latin American-United States cooperation, Brazilian economic planning. Personal correspondence.
  - Brazil - De Barros, Adhemar, 1947-1956 (Box 15, Folder 107)
    Former governor of the state of Sao Paulo, jailed in 1956 for embezzlement. Letters of thanks from Governor DeBarros to NAR for NAR's receiving a De Barros aide. Clippings.
  - Brazil - De Carvalho, Daniel, Dr., 1949-1951 (Box 15, Folder 108)
    Former Secretary of Agriculture in Brazil, assisted United States Embassy. Correspondence re: visit to United States, Eleazar Carvalhos' art education.
  - Brazil - Dutra, Eurico Gaspar, 1943-1964 (Box 15, Folder 109)
    Minister of War, later President of Brazil. Memos and correspondence re" President Dutra's visit to the United States; personal correspondence; memo on Brazilian-United sTates trade treaties.
  - Brazil - Father Saboia School of Industrial Engineering, Sao Paulo, 1948-1951 (Box 15, Folder 110)
  - Brazil - Ferraz. Olavo Amaral, 1950-1961 (Box 15, Folder 111)
    Director of EMA. Correspondence re: NAR helping locate United States college for Ferraz granddaughter; personal correspondence and congratulations on marriage of son.
  - Brazil - Figueiredo, Assis, 1945-1958 (Box 15, Folder 112)
    Worked with NAR during WWII. Appeal to NAR to help so find job in United States and NAR's efforts. Announcement of daughter's engagement; personal correspondence, with some discussions of NAR Latin American activities.
  - Brazil - Films, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 113)
    Correspondence and memos re: use of films to convey anti-Communist message to Brazilian workers. Printed material included.
  - Brazil - Finbaras, S. A., 1952-1953 (Box 16, Folder 114)
    Monthly reports and other financial statements of Finbaras, S. A., a company dedicated to investment in and economic development of Brazil.
  - Brazil - Gainza, Paz A., 1947 (Box 16, Folder 115)
    One piece. Hopes to set up date with NAR.
  - Brazil - Gouthier, Hugo, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 116)
    Consul General of Brazil in New York left to become ambassador in Belgium. Correspondence between him and NAR re: Gouthier's service in New York and visit of Brazilian mayors to New York.
  - Brazil - Government, 1947-1971 (Box 16, Folder 117)
    Memoranda from Berent Friele to NAR re: developments in Brazil, chiefly in Brazil, chiefly 1970-1971. Assorted correspondence dealing with official and non-official matters, much of it pertaining to Brazil's economic situation and development. Clippings also in file.
  - Brazil - Hasslocher, Paulo G., 1945-1949 (Box 16, Folder 118)
    Brazilian ambassador to the Dominican Republic, minister to Panama. Clippings, copy of speech by Hasslocher, and personal correspondence.
  - Brazil - Heilbronner, L. C., 1948-1953 (Box 16, Folder 119)
    Worked in Brazil on International Basic Economy Corporation projects. Personal and business correspondence including possible hiring of Emmett Waddel for position in Brazil.
  - Brazil - Homes, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 120)
    Appeal to support a home for Brazilian boys.
  - Brazil - Hospitals, 1947-1969 (Box 16, Folder 121)
  - Brazil - Immigration, 1946-1947 (Box 16, Folder 122)
    Correspondence between NAR office and Italian Economic, and memoranda re: immigration of Italian farm workers, and other Italian workers to assist in Brazilian economic development.
  - Brazil - Jany, Jose, 1946-1968 (Box 16, Folder 123)
    Connected to work of Office of Inter-American Affairs during WWII. Appeals for NAR assistance in business ventures, United States Government use of an x-ray invention by Jany.
  - Brazil - Kennedy, Donald D. - Boy's Camp, 1946-1948 (Box 16, Folder 124)
    Appeal to NAR for assistance in setting up a boy's camp in Brazil. NAR wrote a letter of introduction for Kennedy.
  - Brazil - Kubitschek de Oliveira, Juscelino, 1951-1966 (Box 16, Folder 125)
    President of Brazil. Among general material are a copy of a biography, correspondence referring to matters of government studies and policy, clippings, and memo re: Kubitschek backed charities. Material from President-elect Kubitschek's trip to United States in 1956, including photos, speech drafts, printed material, entertainment lists, press summary and clippings.
  - Brazil - Lousada, Francisco d'Alamo, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 126)
    Letter.
  - Brazil - Lousada, Luis C. G. and Silva, J. C., 1947-1950 (Box 17, Folder 127)
    Louzada, son of President of Brazil, and Silva were both students at Northern Carolina State College. NAR office, especially Berent Friele, helped students gain admission to the school and financial backing for their studies. Correspondence and clippings.
  - Brazil - Machado, E. S., 1947-1950 (Box 17, Folder 128)
    Member of Brazilian Treasury Delegation in New York and a correspondent for Correls da Noite. NAR declines to give son a letter of recommendation. Correspondence thanking NAR for his work, sending clippings of article Machado wrote, asking NAR to answer some questions for an article.
  - Brazil - Maciel Filho, Jose Soares, Dr., 1951-1955 (Box 17, Folder 129)
    Correspondence with NAR re: Brazilian economic and political situation.
  - Brazil - Magalhaes, Juracy, 1964-1967 (Box 17, Folder 130)